<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Lehman College WiCS</title>
 <link href="lehmanwics.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="lehmanwics.github.io"/>
 <updated>2018-10-14T14:56:23-04:00</updated>
 <id>lehmanwics.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>LC WiCS</name>
   <email>lehmanwics@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Road to GHC18: A Preparation Guide for the Grace Hopper Celebration</title>
   <link href="lehmanwics.github.io/2018/09/16/road-to-ghc-a-preparation-guide-for-the-grace-hopper-celebration"/>
   <updated>2018-09-16T07:34:21-04:00</updated>
   <id>lehmanwics.github.io/2018/09/16/road-to-ghc-a-preparation-guide-for-the-grace-hopper-celebration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So you’re going to the Grace Hopper Celebration. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is here to help you make the most of your experience. Whether your goal is to attend the talks and workshops, meet professors and students in academia, network with other women in tech, or land a job/internships; we hope to guide you to that goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things, first: packing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-bring&quot;&gt;What to Bring:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pack light for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will bring home &lt;strong&gt;tons&lt;/strong&gt; of swag! Last year, my bag was packed to the brim with water bottles, totes, t-shirts, puzzles, exercise bands, travel bottles, etc. Anything you can think of, I brought it home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;luggage&quot;&gt;Luggage&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the trip is only three days, you can get away with bringing a large backpack or duffel. However, I would advise instead to pack a &lt;strong&gt;light backpack&lt;/strong&gt; that’s comfortable to carry around with you at the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, you want something to wear on your back because you’ll be toting around resumes, business cards, possibly a scarf or sweater if it gets cold, and of course, your free conference swag. It’s going to get tiresome to carry all of that in your hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second and last piece of luggage is a &lt;strong&gt;carry-on duffel or rolling suitcase/tote&lt;/strong&gt; to bring on the plane. This &lt;em&gt;should not be checked luggage&lt;/em&gt;. Avoid your luggage getting lost and your conference attire getting lost with it. Make sure the duffel or tote meet’s your airline’s requirements for carry-on baggage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;electronics&quot;&gt;Electronics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, bring a &lt;strong&gt;laptop and laptop charger&lt;/strong&gt; with you. If you don’t have a laptop, that’s okay. The business center at your hotel should have computers available for you to access and print documents. If you’re staying at a popular hotel, you’ll want to get to the business center early in the morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t forget your phone and email on it as well as &lt;strong&gt;2&lt;/strong&gt; chargers! Yes, two. One to bring to the conference (which you may or may not lose) and one to leave in your hotel room. You can probably count on picking up a free charger from conference swag too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consider packing an e-reader or iPad for the plane ride. Whatever you prefer. Paper books are great too :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;attire&quot;&gt;Attire&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference is pretty laid back in terms of dress and the attire I’ve seen ranges from business professional (usually speakers) to casual. You want to be somewhere in the middle of this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are interviewing or expecting to interview at GHC, ask the company rep about interview attire so you can gauge what’s appropriate for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bottoms, err on the side of caution and pack &lt;strong&gt;two semi-dressy pants (think chinos) or a flattering skirt&lt;/strong&gt; (about knee-length), if you prefer. &lt;strong&gt;Dresses&lt;/strong&gt; are perfectly fine too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For tops, pack &lt;strong&gt;two blouses (or at least 1)&lt;/strong&gt;. Doesn’t have to be fancy in any way or overly dressy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, you’ll find you can probably get away with a t-shirt and jeans the entire team but it really does depend on the company you’re interviewing with. Business casual is a good “in the middle” bet so you’re not overdressed or under-dressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Besides, you will have enough t-shirts from swag to wear throughout the conference! Just in case, have a t-shirt you can throw on and a pair of jeans to switch into for night events and dinners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For &lt;strong&gt;shoes&lt;/strong&gt;, one pair of &lt;strong&gt;nice flats&lt;/strong&gt; that are comfortable to walk around in as well as a &lt;strong&gt;pair of sneakers&lt;/strong&gt; is great. Socks as well for those sneakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the airport, wear some shoes you can easily remove (ideally those sneakers just mentioned) and whatever clothes are comfortable to sit in for several hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flip-flops&lt;/strong&gt; for the shower. Thank me later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the bare minimum. You should wear whatever you feel most comfortable in that represents you. Of course, you are welcomed to bring more clothing with you but leave some room for whatever you will be taking back with you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For effective packing, &lt;strong&gt;roll&lt;/strong&gt;, don’t fold your clothing. Saves a lot of space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus: your hotel may have a pool you can take a relaxing swim in later! Drop in a swimsuit for good measure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;essentials&quot;&gt;Essentials&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resumes&lt;/strong&gt; and a nice padfolio. The 99 cent store usually has these for cheap. Otherwise, pick up a plastic and rigid folder to hold those resumes in. Count on bringing at least 40 copies just to be sure. Also check how many companies you’re interested in and bring enough to cover all of them. You will have some resumes left over and that’s okay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper and pen (or two)&lt;/strong&gt;. You might find yourself taking notes during an interview or session. Alternatively, bring your laptop to take notes. However, I find using my phone or laptop to take notes makes it seem like I’m distracted and impolite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Toiletries&lt;/strong&gt; like toothpaste, toothbrush, lotion, and hair-care products in travel-sized containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fellow curly haired gals, hotel toiletries will &lt;em&gt;ruin&lt;/em&gt; your hair. I pack my Deva-Curl and Tahlia Waajid concoction in a small travel bottle. My hair usually lasts 3 days worn natural so I can get away with a small amount to wash and go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Should you wear your hair natural?&lt;/em&gt; Heck yes! I did the entire conference last year. It’s hair, &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; hair. Wear it with pride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you wear your hair straight, pack your favorite hair styling tool because the hair dryer in your hotel bathroom probably won’t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mints and mouthwash&lt;/strong&gt; because you’ll be eating food throughout the conference and want to keep your breath fresh. You might forget you’re chewing gum and forget to spit out so refrain from gum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview&lt;/strong&gt; or other interview prep material so you can get a few study sessions in before interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water bottle&lt;/strong&gt; because although you will probably get a free one, the one you bring from home is already cleaned and washed and the perfect size for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;emergency-items&quot;&gt;Emergency Items&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A small sewing kit is a good idea although not entirely necessary if you pack a back-up outfit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;what-not-to-pack&quot;&gt;What NOT to pack:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High heels. Unless you’re keen on wearing them all day long and can comfortably wear them for long periods of time without wobbling, spare yourself the pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything that could trip security at the airport. I once brought 3-inch blunt scissors (forgot them in my pens container) and was stopped by security to search my bag. Seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Light backpack (to carry during the conference)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Carry-on duffel or small rolling tote&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Laptop, laptop charger (if available)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phone and 2 phone chargers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 semi-dressy pants (skirt or dress OK too), 2 blouses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;T-shirts and a pair of jeans for dinner events&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 pair of sneakers and 1 pair of flats or nice shoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leggings or comfortable jeans and comfortable top for airport&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Flip-flops (for shower and walking in hotel room)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Resumes - 40 copies + padfolio or rigid folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Paper and pen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Necessary toiletries (see above)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mints and moutwash&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview/other interview prep&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Water bottle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t pack uncomfortable shoes like high heels&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leave sharp scissors at home (see above)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resumes&quot;&gt;Resumes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your resume is the most important representation of yourself. This is the only thing sponsors will have to go off of in the beginning before they meet you in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure it shines, represents the best possible you, and works for what you’re applying to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may want to consider having different versions of your resume especially if you’re considering different positions and have varying experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, &lt;strong&gt;if you’re applying for business analyst positions&lt;/strong&gt; you want to highlight skills, accomplishments, and project aspects that emphasize skills necessary for a business analyst role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re applying for software engineering&lt;/strong&gt;, make sure to include relevant skills and technologies you are &lt;strong&gt;comfortable&lt;/strong&gt; speaking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Never&lt;/strong&gt; add any project, language, or technology to your resume that you are not comfortable talking about or explaining as you will inevitably be asked a question about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you ran a handful of SQL queries in MySQL Workbench before but are not entirely familiar with SQL, don’t add SQL to your list of languages and technologies. Instead, add what &lt;strong&gt;you used SQL for&lt;/strong&gt; in the description of your project on your resume.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a way to say you’ve used the language or technology before but not completely familiar with the technology although you are capable of picking it up if given a more in-depth project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, &lt;strong&gt;upload your revised resume to the GHC database a week and a few days before the conference.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;game-plan&quot;&gt;Game Plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re there for the talks and workshops or to land a job or internship, you need a game plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have three days and you want to get the most out of that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re there for networking&lt;/strong&gt;, take a look at the talks and sessions that are open and register for the ones that interest you and are in line with what you’re interested in learning more about. Chances are, the people you are looking to connect with will share similar interests and you can find them at those sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same applies &lt;strong&gt;if you’re there for&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;talks and workshops&lt;/strong&gt;. Find the sessions you want to attend and that are interesting to you and register for them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep in mind that things come up and you may not be able to attend everything. In this case, take note of the sessions that will be recorded and consider skipping these as you can view them online later. You want to be in the sessions that are only available during GHC and won’t be recorded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re there for &lt;strong&gt;finding grad school opportunities or landing an interview/job&lt;/strong&gt;, then you have several options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;researching&quot;&gt;Researching&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you get to GHC, you want to do research on the companies/ schools/institutions you’re interested in and write down their booth number from the Career Fair map here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://s23.a2zinc.net/Clients/abi/ghc2018/public/eventmap.aspx?thumbnail=1#&quot; title=&quot;https://s23.a2zinc.net/Clients/abi/ghc2018/public/eventmap.aspx?thumbnail=1#&quot;&gt;https://s23.a2zinc.net/Clients/abi/ghc2018/public/eventmap.aspx?thumbnail=1#&lt;/a&gt; (choose Career Fair and use the search on the left).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write down a few important things to remember about each company so you know why you chose them. You’ll also want to make note of the programs and/or positions they have available that are of interest to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t wait to apply or be found!&lt;/strong&gt; Positions are open now for most companies so go to their career pages and apply with your best resume. They can look you up in the resume database afterward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Find recruiters on LinkedIn from these companies&lt;/strong&gt; and connect with them to see if they’ll be at the conference so you can meet them. Check out our Slack for a good template for this we pinned to the general channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;career-fair-plan&quot;&gt;Career Fair Plan&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have a list of the companies you’re interested in, you have two options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Order them by least interested to most interested and create a navigation path so that you are going first to the company you are interested in but okay with not getting an offer from them, and ending up last at the company you are &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; excited to join. This will give you an opportunity to get the jitters out and practice your elevator pitch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Alternatively, you can reverse this list and practice your elevator pitch with friends before the conference and then go to the companies that interest you the most first.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In the interest of time and accounting for the nature of a GHC career fair, it’s best to choose option 2 for career opportunities and option 1 for grad school opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The career fair (expo hall) runs from Wednesday to Friday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday it opens at 11:30 am and closes at 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thursday, runs from 9 am to 5:30 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friday, from 9 am to 2pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They keynote is Wednesday morning and then the career fair is open after. Many people may want to go to lunch soon after and then go to the career fair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you want to maximize your opportunities&lt;/strong&gt;, take advantage of this time on Wednesday and go to the career fair right after the keynote. Because top company booths usually get pretty swamped, you may have to deal with lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the day you want to spend the most time at the career fair so you can schedule interviews appropriately. Make a goal to land at least one interview from the career hall (or any number that’s best for you) and pick up some swag along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take 20 minute breaks to decompress and relax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you already have a couple of interviews scheduled, try to spend only half your time at the career fair on Wednesday and enjoy some speaker sessions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If possible, make note of when you see crowds dying down (like during lunch, for example, may not happen) so you can use those times on Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have an interview scheduled, make a point to introduce yourself to the people at the company booth you’re interviewing with and let them know you’re excited for the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick up where you left off the day before and head to the career fair first if you haven’t landed as many interviews as you’d like. Make sure to grab some breakfast and leave time toward the end of the day to sit in on a workshop or speaker session of your choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you feel you already have enough interviews scheduled, walk around the career fair and check out new companies you hadn’t considered. Use this time for casual talk. Alternatively, find friends you can chill with for a bit before studying for any of your interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Friday&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you don’t have any interviews yet&lt;/strong&gt;, don’t fret! Keep working your way through the career fair and learn more about what opportunities work for you. Consider companies on the outskirts and with smaller booths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re maxed out on interviews&lt;/strong&gt;, and you’ve landed an offer you are strongly considering accepting, then enjoy the last day of the conference! Or not, up to you. :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interviews&quot;&gt;Interviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid scheduling interviews back-to-back&lt;/strong&gt;. This will likely drain you and leave you exhausted and wanting to go back to your room.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave at least 2 hours in between interviews so you can eat and relax before the next one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid scheduling more than 2 or 3 interviews a day&lt;/strong&gt;. 3 is a lot for anyone as it could potentially be 3 hours all together of exercising your brain. However, you know yourself best and should understand your limits. Do the most you can and make time to decompress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ideally, it is best to interview on-site as offers are usually given same-day or the day after. If you find yourself overwhelmed with interviews, let the rep know and ask if it can be moved to a later date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you have not or are currently taking data structures&lt;/strong&gt;, let your interviewer know at, &lt;strong&gt;not before the interview&lt;/strong&gt; so they can set their own expectations of what questions you should be able to answer completely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interview-prep&quot;&gt;Interview Prep&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Study your resume really well and be prepared to be asked any question about what’s on your resume. Here are questions I’ve been asked:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explain your GPA (It was a 3.7 instead of a 4.0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tell me more about this project and what was difficult about it?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is the difference between Python and Java? (&lt;em&gt;Python is interpreted while Java is compiled. Although both compile to bytecode but Python’s compilation is implicit because you don’t invoke a compiler as you would in Java&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve mastered your resume, review prep packages sent to you by companies you’re interviewing with and check out interview reports on Glassdoor to get a sense of what type of questions you’ll be asked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;technical&quot;&gt;Technical&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are doing a technical interview&lt;/strong&gt;, and short on time, prepare for data structures and algorithms questions by reviewing Strings &amp;amp; Arrays in Hackerrank and be comfortable with at least two other data structures (Stacks, HashMaps, ArrayLists) that can be implemented efficiently to solve a variety of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have at least a month left before GHC (at this point, you only have a week) try to do at least 2 easy and 2 medium hackerranks per day and throw in a couple of hard ones throughout the week if you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understand OOP principles and be able to explain them to a non-technical user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, brush up on basic syntax using the language you are most comfortable with. Not knowing a specific method in a class is fine but not ending a Java statement with a colon is harder to let slide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That said, try to stick to &lt;strong&gt;one&lt;/strong&gt; programming language so you avoid crossing and confusing yourself during interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cracking The Coding Interview&lt;/strong&gt; is the best book to narrow down specific questions to review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;behavioral&quot;&gt;Behavioral&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re doing a behavioral interview&lt;/strong&gt;, understand they are geared toward learning more about you and how you communicate, as well as how you would fit in with their team or company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do your research and know how to answer the &lt;strong&gt;“Why this company?”&lt;/strong&gt; question. Know what the company does and go to their careers site to learn about their culture. Pick out the things you most connect with and share them as reasons you would like to work there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be genuine with your answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The dreaded &lt;strong&gt;“Tell me about yourself?”&lt;/strong&gt; question is an opportunity to share things that aren’t on your resume like interesting hobbies and accomplishments as well as how your skills fit into the role you’re applying to. In general this question really means “What’s interesting about you and why should we hire you?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s OK to be nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t have to answer question right away. You can always say, “hmm, let me think on this for a few seconds”. Collect your thoughts and thoughtfully respond. You don’t want to rush an answer you’re not ready to give.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you need clarification, ask for it. Ask for a question to be repeated or better yet, repeat the question back to them in the way you understood it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, “Do you mean, X?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This allows the interviewer to review your understanding of the question and rephrase it if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also want to treat this as a conversation. Smile. Chuckle if the interviewer is funny. These are people just like you. They want to be connected in some way and find something to latch on to to make it easier to move you forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ask thoughtful questions like:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s the best part about working at X company for you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What led you to deciding to work at X company over any other company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When did you start here and what’s been the most interesting part of working here so far?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What’s your advice for anyone starting new at X company?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What traits describe someone who is excellent in this position? (&lt;em&gt;To gauge the kind of candidate they’re looking for - you can piggy back off of this to let them know how you fit that profile&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;strong&gt;is not&lt;/strong&gt; the ideal time to ask about compensation, relocation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;you do&lt;/strong&gt;, want to ask questions that are important for you to learn about the company (typically also asked during an HR screening call).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in continued learning opportunities, ask about what their culture around continued learning is and what resources (if any) are available to employees looking to increase their technical knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in mentoring, ask if they have a mentoring structure in place or how interns/full-times get on-boarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, you want to ask questions that benefit you as well as questions that connect with the interviewer as a person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid&lt;/strong&gt; sarcasm, jokes in poor taste, or anything you are doubtful about mentioning or saying that may seem inappropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;self-care&quot;&gt;Self-Care&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GHC can be a overwhelming experiences. It’s a large conference with 10,000+ people and although everyone will be spread out, it’s perfectly normal to feel lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start getting overwhelmed, take some time to regenerate and relax. Sit down and watch some funny videos, go through Instagram, do something mindless. Read a chapter of your favorite book. Call you mom to catch up during the conference. Take a nap. Eat a snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anything to get your energy back up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t want to be drained halfway into the day so taking breaks is important to stay alert and focused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep your goals for the day in mind and drown out everything else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create a chat group with friends at the conference so you all can meet up during breaks and talk about your experience so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Share tips! Make more friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;swag&quot;&gt;Swag&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, if you’re there (partly) for the free stuff, this is for you. If you wait until the last day (Friday) an hour or so before the career fair closes, sponsors usually want to get rid of any swag they’ve brought with them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take them up on the offer! This is also a cool opportunity to make last minute connections.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>July - August 2018 Events & Opportunities</title>
   <link href="lehmanwics.github.io/2018/07/18/july-august-2018-events-opportunities"/>
   <updated>2018-07-18T21:06:44-04:00</updated>
   <id>lehmanwics.github.io/2018/07/18/july-august-2018-events-opportunities</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A little late with this month’s events so we are combining the remainder of July &amp;amp; August so you can take advantage of these events before the summer ends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy! P.S. Check out our Slack chat to talk more about events you’re interested in attending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunity-pwc-grace-hopper-sponsorship-application&quot;&gt;[OPPORTUNITY] PwC Grace Hopper Sponsorship Application&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing (“GHC”) is the one of the world’s largest annual gatherings of women technologists. PwC is sponsoring rising female college sophomores or juniors who are interested in pursuing a career in consulting to attend the GHC18 Conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be considered for PwC’s GHC18 sponsorship, please fill out the application below.  Completion of the PwC GHC18 Sponsorship Application does not constitute a formal expression of interest in employment opportunities with the firm. Individuals interested in pursuing employment opportunities with PwC can do so at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pwc.com/us/en/careers/campus.html&quot; title=&quot;http://www.pwc.com/us/en/careers/campus.html&quot;&gt;http://www.pwc.com/us/en/careers/campus.html&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selected students will be notified by August 31st.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScLptCdZ_XJXf9gtiU9-GKsu5LYAupd1AFO_pHIhQD8FvwWCQ/viewform&quot; title=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScLptCdZ_XJXf9gtiU9-GKsu5LYAupd1AFO_pHIhQD8FvwWCQ/viewform&quot;&gt;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScLptCdZ_XJXf9gtiU9-GKsu5LYAupd1AFO_pHIhQD8FvwWCQ/viewform&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunity-google-travel-grant-application-2018-grace-hopper-conference--apply-now&quot;&gt;[OPPORTUNITY] Google Travel Grant Application: 2018 Grace Hopper Conference – Apply Now&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfX4FAnxUgZZCt6gWkJ5RH3sHsrkaOeHjbnn8SHUq8POoKp_g/viewform&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please apply here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;by July 22nd at 11:59pm PDT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of Google’s ongoing commitment to increase the number of women in engineering, we are excited to offer travel grants to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gracehopper.org/&quot;&gt;2018 Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing Conference&lt;/a&gt; taking place in Houston, TX from Sept 26-28th. Once again, this year’s conference will offer incredible opportunities for mentoring, networking and career development.&lt;br /&gt;
University students and industry professionals in the US and Canada who are excelling in computer science and passionate about supporting women in tech can apply for a travel grant to attend the 2018 Grace Hopper conference.&lt;br /&gt;
The Grace Hopper Travel Sponsorship includes:Round trip flight to Houston,TX (from within the US or Canada)Conference registrationReimbursement for ground transportation to and from the airport and the hotel Arranged hotel accommodations from Sept 25-29$100 USD reimbursement for miscellaneous travel costsA fun event specifically for travel grant recipients on one of the evenings of the conference!&lt;br /&gt;
The Grace Hopper Travel Sponsorship winners will be announced by mid-August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For questions, please email &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ghctravelgrant@google.com&quot;&gt;ghctravelgrant@google.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://students.googleblog.com/2018/07/google-travel-grant-application-2018.html&quot; title=&quot;https://students.googleblog.com/2018/07/google-travel-grant-application-2018.html&quot;&gt;https://students.googleblog.com/2018/07/google-travel-grant-application-2018.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunity-2018-grace-hopper-fellowship&quot;&gt;[OPPORTUNITY] 2018 Grace Hopper Fellowship&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Application closes Sunday, August 12 @ 11:59pm (PST)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Accelerated interviews for 2019 full-time and internship opportunities. For students who receive and accept an offer, Twitter will provide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Student registration to #GHC18, roundtrip travel, lodging and meal stipend for the 4-day trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pre-conference experience with senior leaders at an event-only surprise event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exclusive access to Twitter events throughout the week with Twitter engineers, @TwitterWomen (our Women Employee Resource Group), and leadership throughout the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018gracehopperfellowship.splashthat.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://2018gracehopperfellowship.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;https://2018gracehopperfellowship.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-how-to-get-hired-as-a-software-engineer&quot;&gt;[FREE] How to get Hired as a Software Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Friday, July 20, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM to 9:00 PM @ Codesmith - 250 Lafayette Street · New York, NY_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. The 5 key things you need to know to get hired as a mid-level software engineer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. How to whiteboard through the typical coding challenges that make up 50% of most technical interviews&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number of opportunities for software engineers is booming but to get a mid level position and above requires a special kind of preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this interactive workshop we cover the five key skills that you must have in order to succeed in the job search including how to effectively whiteboard through the tough coding interviews.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session will help you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Identify your career and role priorities - for example, are you most interested in a career as a backend or frontend developer, within an established corporation or a new start-up?​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Understand and prepare the five key skills that you must have in order to succeed in the job search for software engineering positions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Understand how to approach the job search so you find the job that is best suited to your skills and aspirations.​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Whiteboarding - working through coding problems on a whiteboard is a crucial part of most interviews. You’ll see how to effectively whiteboard and work through problems live in pairs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you at what promises to be an unmissable evening for anyone pursuing employment as a software engineer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Build-with-Code-New-York/events/252915202/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Build-with-Code-New-York/events/252915202/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/Build-with-Code-New-York/events/252915202/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-nyc-internapalooza&quot;&gt;[FREE] NYC Internapalooza&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Sunday, July 22&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2:00pm @ 63 5th Ave – (5th between 13th and 14th) New York, NY_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internapalooza, the largest gathering of interns, young engineers, and STEM students around the world, is coming to New York City! Over 20,000 students from colleges across the nation have signed up for previous events across the nation. We come together to meet fantastic companies, converse with fellow interns, learn from remarkable visionaries, and forge connections between one another that will define the future. Our world was formed by brilliant people but we will push it forward by building the greatest network the world has ever seen! Come start an incredible journey with your fellow interns as we takeover downtown NYC and start helping each other build an insanely great future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://2018nycinternapalooza.splashthat.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://2018nycinternapalooza.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;https://2018nycinternapalooza.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-data-science-in-30-minutes-the-accidental-data-scientist&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Data Science in 30 Minutes: The Accidental Data Scientist&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, July 24, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:30 PM – 6:30 PM EDT @ Online_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thedataincubator.com/&quot;&gt;The Data Incubator&lt;/a&gt; and Katrina Riehl, Director of Data Science at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.homeaway.com/&quot;&gt;HomeAway.com&lt;/a&gt;, for the July 2018 installment of our free monthly webinar series, Data Science in 30 minutes: The Accidental Data Scientist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; Katrina will detail the journey her career has taken from researcher and software developer to Data Scientist. She will explain how her technology roles and skills have evolved as this new discipline emerged over the last decade. First, starting out as a young Python and Artificial Intelligence enthusiast and eventually after many years, finally embracing Data Science as a discipline, and leading a strong and diverse Data Science team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-science-in-30-minutes-the-accidental-data-scientist-with-katrina-riehl-director-of-data-tickets-45736046747?aff=ehomecard&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-science-in-30-minutes-the-accidental-data-scientist-with-katrina-riehl-director-of-data-tickets-45736046747?aff=ehomecard&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-science-in-30-minutes-the-accidental-data-scientist-with-katrina-riehl-director-of-data-tickets-45736046747?aff=ehomecard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-wow-x-sci-fi-wednesdays-women-of-wearable-technology-vrar-edition&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;W.O.W x SCI-FI Wednesdays (Women of Wearable Technology): VR/AR Edition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wed, July 25, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM – 9:00 PM EDT - SAP Leonardo Center, 10 Hudson Yards, 48th Fl., New York, NY 10001_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us next week for &lt;strong&gt;WOW x SCI-FI Wednesday: VR/AR Edition&lt;/strong&gt;as we partner with SAP Next Gen to talk about all things Virtual Reality. We will have an engaging panel discussion on VR, AR, MR, XR, their connection to wearables and the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This month’s panel:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johanna Salazar- Two Goats&lt;br /&gt;
LaJuné McMillian - LaJuné&lt;br /&gt;
Jen Salavarrieta- SVRF&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hosted by Greg Dietz- SAP Next Gen&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moderated by Amanda McIntyre Chavis -NY Ambassador of Women of Wearables&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6:00-6:30p&lt;/strong&gt; Check-In/Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6:30-7:30p&lt;/strong&gt; Panel discussion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7:30-8:30p&lt;/strong&gt; Q&amp;amp;A/ Sci-Fi Workshop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wow-x-sci-fi-wednesdays-women-of-wearable-technology-vrar-edition-tickets-48140661013?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wow-x-sci-fi-wednesdays-women-of-wearable-technology-vrar-edition-tickets-48140661013?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wow-x-sci-fi-wednesdays-women-of-wearable-technology-vrar-edition-tickets-48140661013?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-summer-of-tech--rooftop-mixer&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Summer of Tech | Rooftop Mixer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Wednesday, July 25, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM to 9:00 PM @ The DL Rooftop Lounge&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun is out and so are we,&lt;br /&gt;
to celebrate with our tech community!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developers &amp;amp; Engineers will join us in spades,&lt;br /&gt;
to mix and mingle with those in their trades.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come drink with DevOps, Jive with Javas,&lt;br /&gt;
Mingle with Mobiles and Swing with Scalas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** More details coming soon – RSVP to stay in the loop **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/techinmotionnyc/events/251681209/&quot; title=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/techinmotionnyc/events/251681209/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/techinmotionnyc/events/251681209/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-tech-talks-primetime-intern-edition&quot;&gt;[FREE] Tech Talks Primetime: Intern Edition&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Thursday, July 26th, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 pm - 8:30 pm @ BuzzFeed, 111 E 18th Street, 13th Floor, New York NY 10003_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;BuzzFeed Tech Talks&lt;/strong&gt; is BuzzFeed’s speaker series where we gather with the rest of the NYC tech community and discuss topics that matter to all of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time, we’ll be focusing on interns! Ask the questions you’ve always wanted to ask in a panel with BuzzFeed’s recruiting team. Hear from a BuzzFeed software engineer about his experience transitioning from an intern to a full-time employee. Mingle with other interns and enjoy some light snacks and drinks. We hope to see you there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://buzzfeedtechtalks.splashthat.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://buzzfeedtechtalks.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;https://buzzfeedtechtalks.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-visualizing-data-for-greater-impact&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Visualizing Data for Greater Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Thu, July 26, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;12:00 PM – 1:30 PM EDT @ Pratt Institute - 144 West 14th Street_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join Pratt Center’s GIS Specialist Sadra Shahab on July 26th for a complimentary training on how you and your organization can maximize Pratt Center’s Neighborhood Data Portal to visualize data in an impactful way and practice data-responsive program design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you’ll learn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get to know and work with a variety of demographic and non-demographic data layers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Master the capabilities of all tools&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to draw on and customize your own map for print&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How to select data and export selected information as excel tables, which allows for greater data processing and other visualization options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this training will focus on the fundamentals of using the data portal, we will also include tips and insights into how spatial data can strengthen and support healthy program development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited, so please RSVP. There is no cap on the number of attendees from one single organization, but if you are interested in bringing a group of five or more, please contact Salvador Muñoz at Pratt Center (&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:smunoz@prattcenter.net&quot;&gt;smunoz@prattcenter.net&lt;/a&gt;) so we can accommodate you better. All attendees are encouraged to bring laptops to access the portal while the training runs. There will be Wi-Fi access. Light food and refreshments will be served.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Neighborhood Data Portal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created in 2016, the Neighborhood Data Portal (NDP) is a free online application that integrates nearly three dozen vital datasets to break down New York City’s neighborhoods by the numbers. By democratizing access to essential planning tools like mapping and data analysis, the portal advances Pratt Center’s mission to support low-moderate income communities to plan for the future they want to see. Essential updgrades made to the platform in 2018 now give users, especially staff at community-based organizations, greater analytical control over the data they need to develop responsive, impactful programs and customize and share their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/visualizing-data-for-greater-impact-tickets-47183123994?aff=garysguide&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/visualizing-data-for-greater-impact-tickets-47183123994?aff=garysguide&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/visualizing-data-for-greater-impact-tickets-47183123994?aff=garysguide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-the-bronx-night-market&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;The Bronx Night Market&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Sat, July 28, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4:00 PM – 9:00 PM EDT @ Fordham Plaza_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BX is getting its Night Market, and it’s a big deal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first-ever Bronx Night Market is taking place this summer, at Fordham Plaza. With more than 35 handpicked food vendors, it represents the city’s diverse culinary offerings and stands to be the biggest of its kind in the boogie down. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The monthly, FREE, open-air festival is a collaboration between quarterly magazine &lt;a href=&quot;http://ediblebronx.ediblecommunities.com/&quot;&gt;Edible Bronx&lt;/a&gt; and Bronx-based &lt;a href=&quot;https://blox.nyc/&quot;&gt;creative agency BLOX&lt;/a&gt; with support from the Fordham BID. It highlights local artisans, merchants and of course, the local soundtrack with notable performers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re in search of unique food items, packaged treats or an authentic recipe passed down for generations, The Bronx Night Market has over 35 food vendors, handcrafted items, art merchants, and live entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;vendors&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vendors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bronx Brewery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bronx Beer Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creme and Cocoa Creamery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CaSpanish&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charlies Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;City Tamale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Espresso State Of Mind&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Empanology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Freshly Made&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grace’s Culinary Specialties&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Habanero Mexican Cuisine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In Patella&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lotsa Latkes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lolo’s Seafood Shack&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MP Fish Fry &amp;amp; Soul&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Next Stop Vegan&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebecca Sweet &amp;amp; Spice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rib In A Cup&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scoops In Cahoots&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sweet Milk &amp;amp; Sugar Desserts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Bronx Public&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fried Kitchen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Tea Factor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tradita // Cka Ka Qellu&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tripla Panna Ice Cream&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Porkcue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port Morris Distillery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes Desserts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All food, drink and merchant vendors are selling their items and setting their own price.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;No tickets or entry fee, just come hungry.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/the-bronx-night-market-tickets-45370148335?aff=ehomecard&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/the-bronx-night-market-tickets-45370148335?aff=ehomecard&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/the-bronx-night-market-tickets-45370148335?aff=ehomecard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-am-i-or-can-i-be-a-data-scientist&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Am I, or Can I be a Data Scientist?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Mon, July 30, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM – 8:00 PM EDT @ Galvanize_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a discussion about how to start a career in data science. You’ll leave this event with a clear perspective and structured options for beginning your career in this quickly-growing field. You will also have a list of the best resources available to use to plan your studies with Galvanize!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This program is for people who are serious about becoming data scientists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course, you’ll learn the tools, techniques, and fundamental concepts you need to know to make an impact as a data scientist. You’ll work through messy, real-world data sets to gain experience across the data science stack: data munging, exploration, modeling, validation, visualization, and communication. Our unique setting in the Galvanize community of startups and tech companies is the perfect place to learn and expand your network!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more at &lt;a href=&quot;https://new.galvanize.com/new-york/data-science&quot; title=&quot;https://new.galvanize.com/new-york/data-science&quot;&gt;https://new.galvanize.com/new-york/data-science&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/am-i-or-can-i-be-a-data-scientist-tickets-45082413713?aff=ebapi&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/am-i-or-can-i-be-a-data-scientist-tickets-45082413713?aff=ebapi&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/am-i-or-can-i-be-a-data-scientist-tickets-45082413713?aff=ebapi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-learn-to-code-nyc-intro-to-html--css-workshop&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Learn to Code NYC: Intro to HTML &amp;amp; CSS Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, July 31, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:45 PM – 8:45 PM EDT @ Galvanize_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ome learn or review the first concepts you need to build web pages: HTML and CSS. This intro to HTML/CSS assumes nothing and provides the conceptual tools you need to kickstart your learning. This is also your invitation to come hang out, network, and grow with our community of motivated learners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;youll-walk-away-with-a-few-invaluable-tools&quot;&gt;You’ll walk away with a few invaluable tools:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An introduction to HTML and CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Simple analogies to help you learn and teach others&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Modeling skills necessary to think like a programmer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;requirements&quot;&gt;Requirements:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Growth Mindset&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A computer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;An enthusiasm for both learning and talking about the web&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/learn-to-code-nyc-intro-to-html-css-workshop-tickets-45974880104?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/learn-to-code-nyc-intro-to-html-css-workshop-tickets-45974880104?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/learn-to-code-nyc-intro-to-html-css-workshop-tickets-45974880104?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-women--diversity-in-blockchain-data-science--ai---challenges--opportunites&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Women &amp;amp; Diversity In Blockchain, Data Science &amp;amp; A.I. - Challenges &amp;amp; Opportunites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, July 31, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM – 9:00 PM EDT @ Rise New York, 43 West 23rd Street, New York, NY 10010_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check out our other events and training sessions:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot; title=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a community discussion around the challenges and opportunities for broader diversity and inclusion within the blockchain, data science and A.I. space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Also, sign up to our upcoming Solidity, Vyper &amp;amp; Web3 training series:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot; title=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://CryptoRockstar.io&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join the official NYC blockchain community&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot; title=&quot;http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://meetup.com/blockchainNYC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/women-diversity-in-blockchain-data-science-ai-challenges-opportunities-tickets-46447554887?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/women-diversity-in-blockchain-data-science-ai-challenges-opportunities-tickets-46447554887?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/women-diversity-in-blockchain-data-science-ai-challenges-opportunities-tickets-46447554887?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-wisp-new-york-chapter-launch---networking-and-focus-group&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;WISP New York Chapter Launch - Networking and Focus Group&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, July 31, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM – 9:00 PM EDT @ PwC NYC_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;join-us-and-help-to-shape-the-future-of-wisp-new-york&quot;&gt;Join us and help to shape the future of WISP New York!&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;women-in-security-and-privacy-wisp-is-excited-to-announce-that-it-is-spreading-more-wispness-to-the-east-coast-with-the-launch-of-wisp-new-york-this-july-wisp-is-partnering-with-pwc-to-bring-you-this-special-launch-event-providing-an-opportunity-to&quot;&gt;Women in Security and Privacy (WISP) is excited to announce that it is spreading more WISPness to the East Coast, with the launch of WISP New York this July! WISP is partnering with PwC to bring you this special launch event, providing an opportunity to:&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn more about WISP and its mission&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meet our new New York co-Chairs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Help provide valuable input to shape the future of WISP NY through a facilitated focus group discussion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will conclude the evening with an opportunity to network with your peers and build important relationships in the community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wisp-new-york-chapter-launch-networking-and-focus-group-tickets-47825827337?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wisp-new-york-chapter-launch-networking-and-focus-group-tickets-47825827337?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/wisp-new-york-chapter-launch-networking-and-focus-group-tickets-47825827337?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-javascript-mini-bootcamp-fundamentals-i-tickets-45904267901&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-javascript-mini-bootcamp-fundamentals-i-tickets-45904267901&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-intro-to-blockchain-sponsored-by-tech-data&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Intro to Blockchain (Sponsored by Tech Data)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wed, August 1, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9:00 AM – 4:00 PM EDT @ Galvanize_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blockchain for business requires trust. It involves a shared ledger, smart contracts, privacy, and proof. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our session will walk you through what differentiates between blockchain used for Bitcoin and the blockchain IBM knows will change the way businesses manage transactions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get hands-on experience building your own Blockchain network! End Users are welcome to join partners in this session, please leverage this opportunity to take that client to the next level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All skill levels are welcome at these hands-on events; you only need to bring a fundamental knowledge of computing, a desire to learn more, and your own laptop for the lab material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details and registration: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/new-york-city-august-1st-intro-to-blockchain-sponsored-by-tech-data-tickets-47568753422?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/new-york-city-august-1st-intro-to-blockchain-sponsored-by-tech-data-tickets-47568753422?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/new-york-city-august-1st-intro-to-blockchain-sponsored-by-tech-data-tickets-47568753422?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-beyond-blockchain--iota-meetup-nyc-x-ga&quot;&gt;[FREE] BEYOND BLOCKCHAIN | IOTA MEETUP NYC X GA&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Thursday, Aug 2&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30–8:30pm EDT @ Galvanize_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IOTA Meetup NYC and General Assembly New York are bringing Beyond Blockchain to GA’s New York HQ.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month, IOTA Meetup NYC’s very own Kevin Chen and Dan Simerman will walk through the upcoming Qubic platform, IXI Hub as it relates to real world adoption in the world of blockchain. Our discussion will revolve around how to take advantage of these upcoming releases, as well as the implications of these tools on the blockchain industry and the economy at large.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This will be equal parts presentation and open forum - so come with your questions and lets discuss the future of distributed ledger tech together!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/education/beyond-blockchain-iota-meetup-nyc-x-ga/new-york-city/54726&quot; title=&quot;https://generalassemb.ly/education/beyond-blockchain-iota-meetup-nyc-x-ga/new-york-city/54726&quot;&gt;https://generalassemb.ly/education/beyond-blockchain-iota-meetup-nyc-x-ga/new-york-city/54726&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-debugging-the-technical-interview&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Debugging the Technical Interview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wed, August 8, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM – 8:30 PM EDT @ Stack Overflow_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How we interview and who we hire has a huge impact on our engineering communities. On one hand we want to reduce risks of a poor fit, on the other hand we don’t want to overlook great people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why should you attend?&lt;/strong&gt; This workshop is focused on improving your skills and processes as a software technical interviewer or hiring manager.&lt;br /&gt;
Using our expertise from conducting over 20,000 interviews, we’ll unpack the hiring process from end-to-end and dig into how to not only improve accuracy and consistency but also raise the bar and level the playing field.&lt;br /&gt;
You’ll leave with specific methods and materials for improving both your interview approach, hiring decisions and candidate experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who should attend?&lt;/strong&gt; Software Engineers, Hiring managers for technical roles and those who are generally passionate about hiring and interviewing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6pm: Doors open&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6:30pm: Workshop begins&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7:30pm-8pm: Q&amp;amp;A + Networking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light appetizers and refreshments will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please have ID available for check-in at the lobby when entering the building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/debugging-the-technical-interview-tickets-48221965196?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/debugging-the-technical-interview-tickets-48221965196?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/debugging-the-technical-interview-tickets-48221965196?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-squarespace-open-house&quot;&gt;[FREE] Squarespace Open House&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_August 8, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6 pm - 9 pm @ Squarespace HQ in NYC_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is intended for Software Engineering students (or related majors) seeking Internships &amp;amp; New Grad opportunities in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you a university student studying Software Engineering (or a related major) seeking Internship or New Grad opportunities for Summer 2019? Swing by to check out our headquarters, learn more about our Internship and New Grad opportunities, and hear about what it’s like to work at Squarespace from our Engineers. Bring your resume for real-time feedback from a Technical Recruiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; Food, drinks, and views from our beautiful rooftop will be provided. &lt;br /&gt;
(IG Story and Snapchat gold)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6pm:&lt;/strong&gt; Office tours and networking&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;6:30pm:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduction to Engineering at Squarespace&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;7:15pm:&lt;/strong&gt; Get to know our Engineering teams and have your resume reviewed by a recruiter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Space is limited, so entry will be granted on a first come, first served basis.&lt;br /&gt;
Please let us know if you’re interested in the form above and we’ll follow up with a confirmation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about our product and company &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.squarespace.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password needed to RSVP. Slack or email lehmanwics@gmail.com for the password.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://campusopenhouse.squarespace.com/&quot; title=&quot;https://campusopenhouse.squarespace.com/&quot;&gt;https://campusopenhouse.squarespace.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-woke-work-the-importance-of-self-care-for-women-of-color&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Woke Work: The Importance of Self-Care for Women of Color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Thu, August 9, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM – 8:30 PM EDT @ Civic Hall_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Civic Women is proud to present Woke Work, a panel of five outstanding women of color including our moderator Ivelyse Andino, CEO and Founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.radical-health.com/&quot;&gt;Radical Health&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Labeled as divas, angry, bitter, and strong — none of which are considered positive attributes — women of color often find themselves confronted with the unfortunate dilemma of whether to illuminate their voices.” -Karima Mariama-Arthur, an attorney and founder of executive consulting firm WordSmithRapport. (Forbes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mental health is a real issue, and it affects our everyday lives. As women of color (WOC) not only do we struggle at home and at work, we suffer in silence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout this event, we’ll discuss the impact of mental health on women of color and explore resources and best practices for attendees to protect and promote their mental health in the workplace. This includes how to approach difficult conversations, holistic treatments and self-care, and maintaining a healthy work-life balance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this panel is geared toward WOC, we welcome all women and our male allies. We strive to create an inclusive community and welcome trans, genderqueer, and non-binary people to all events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101-tickets-45904542723&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101-tickets-45904542723&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101-tickets-45904542723&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-att-entertainment-hackathon---nyc&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;AT&amp;amp;T Entertainment Hackathon - NYC&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Fri, Aug 10, 2018, 5:00 PM – Sat, Aug 11, 2018, 9:30 PM EDT&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Center for Social Innovation_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;are-you-interested-in-entertainment-and-love-to-code-do-you-have-an-idea-for-an-app-that-will-disrupt-the-way-we-experience-consume-or-create-content&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Are you interested in entertainment and love to code? Do you have an idea for an app that will disrupt the way we experience, consume or create content?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then join us on August 10 - 11 for a special Entertainment-themed hackathon produced by the AT&amp;amp;T Developer Program. This event will bring together developers, designers, and creators to hack innovative and disruptive entertainment solutions. You bring the innovative ideas and designs and we’ll bring the tech to help you transform them into apps in just 24 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;you-bring&quot;&gt;You Bring…&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your laptop, skills &amp;amp; ideas. Come with a collaborative, team-focused mindset and/or team-up in advance on Twitter/Facebook/Google+ with &lt;strong&gt;#atthack&lt;/strong&gt;. Whether you are a developer, designer, project manager, or just interested in tech, you are invited to attend this event. Every group needs a good balance of talent and your skills are needed! This event will not feature an onsite team formation component so it’s highly suggest you arrive with a team to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;we-supply&quot;&gt;We Supply…&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quick presentations and code samples that help kick start your hacking, food to keep you going, and caffeine to keep you awake. We will have technical mentors to assist you in building faster, smarter, and with new tools. We will also have loaner hardware on-site for you to use in your solutions.Google Recruiters are coming to our event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/att-entertainment-hackathon-nyc-tickets-47483803334?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/att-entertainment-hackathon-nyc-tickets-47483803334?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/att-entertainment-hackathon-nyc-tickets-47483803334?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-social-good-hackathon&quot;&gt;[FREE] &lt;strong&gt;Social Good Hackathon&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sat, Aug 11, 2018, 8:00 AM – Sun, Aug 12, 2018, 6:00 PM EDT @ Capgemini Accelerated Solutions Environment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have a keen interest in technology and a passion for solving problems? Then look no further!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calling all business people, tech experts, designers, data scientists, thinkers, and doers who are committed to using technology to solve todays business challenges! Join Capgemini and our sponsors for the 2018 Social Good Hackathon – an event where motivated teams of professionals will seek to use technology to help businesses tackle some of the most pressing challenges of our time. Register now and take your first step towards making a social impact!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you want to learn more about cloud technologies? Or gain hands-on experience in one of our workshops led by our technology sponsors? Then this is the place for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The hackathon will feature several specific challenges, provided and judged by our sponsors, that will offer additional prizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please check back on our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.socialgoodhack.com/&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt; over the next month to see what new challenges have been issued!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/social-good-hackathon-tickets-47935425147?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot; title=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/social-good-hackathon-tickets-47935425147?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/social-good-hackathon-tickets-47935425147?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register: &lt;a href=&quot;https://miccapgemini.typeform.com/to/v3WFa0&quot; title=&quot;https://miccapgemini.typeform.com/to/v3WFa0&quot;&gt;https://miccapgemini.typeform.com/to/v3WFa0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>June 2018 Events & Opportunities!</title>
   <link href="lehmanwics.github.io/2018/05/26/june-events"/>
   <updated>2018-05-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>lehmanwics.github.io/2018/05/26/june-events</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Some links courtesy of GirlDevelopIt NYC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the first edition of our summer newsletter series! Each month during the summer we will release a list of local events and opportunities you can participate in. Check out June’s list below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;opportunity-facebook-grace-hopper-scholarship&quot;&gt;[OPPORTUNITY] Facebook Grace Hopper Scholarship&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applications open on Friday, June 1, 2018 at 5:00pm PST.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is committed to advancing women in technology, and we are very excited to announce the 2018 Facebook Grace Hopper Women in Computing Scholarship!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This fall we’ll join thousands of remarkable women in technology in Houston, Texas from September 26-28, 2018 for our eleventh year at the Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing. This unique scholarship program will be awarded to 50 women excelling in Computer Science. Each recipient will have the opportunity not only to attend the Celebration, but to spend valuable days before the conference with Facebook engineers learning, collaborating, and preparing for the conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We look forward to celebrating with you in Houston!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Completed applications are due by Saturday, June 30, 2018 at 12:00am PST.&lt;/strong&gt;
(Applications may be saved and edited up until application deadline)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/careers/program/gracehopper2018&quot;&gt;https://www.facebook.com/careers/program/gracehopper2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-500-women-scientists-wikipedia-edit-a-thon&quot;&gt;[FREE] 500 Women Scientists’ Wikipedia Edit-a-Thon&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sat, June 2, 2018, 2:00 PM – 5:00 PM @ Caveat&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;87% of Wikipedia editors are men. So it’s no surprise most of the scientists on Wikipedia are pale, stale, and male. 500 Women Scientists is working to change that — transforming the idea of what a scientist looks like, online and IRL. Join them at Caveat to learn more about the contributions of trailblazing women scientists while editing the Wikipedia pages they deserve. &lt;em&gt;no experience Wikipedia or web editing needed!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bring your laptop and your sense of righteous indignation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/500-women-scientists-wikipedia-edit-a-thon-tickets-44743622379?aff=ehomecard&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/500-women-scientists-wikipedia-edit-a-thon-tickets-44743622379?aff=ehomecard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;10-june-2018-ny-tech-meetup-and-afterparty&quot;&gt;[$10] June 2018 NY Tech Meetup and Afterparty&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tuesday, June 5, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:00 PM to 9:30 PM @ SVA Theatre - 333 West 23rd Street_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for NYC’s most famous and longest running monthly tech event! You’ll see a fantastic lineup of New York tech companies presenting live demos of their products, followed by an afterparty (sponsored this month by Civic Hall) where you can network with the community and meet our demoers and sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This month we are partnering with Civic Hall to showcase some of NYC’s best civic and social good focused tech!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/ny-tech/events/249977014/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/ny-tech/events/249977014/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-summery-rosé-for-female-freelancers--founders&quot;&gt;[FREE] Summery Rosé for Female Freelancers &amp;amp; Founders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, June 5, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM – 9:00 PM EDT_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join the Sharehive founders for a drink and networking evening for female freelancers and founders looking to grow their professional network and make new friends over Rosé! It will be an intimate evening where you will get the opportunity to connect fellow brilliant women at a private roof-top terrace with the New York skyline as a backdrop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A detailed address for the venue will be shared one day before the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/summery-rose-for-female-freelancers-founders-tickets-46424488896?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/summery-rose-for-female-freelancers-founders-tickets-46424488896?aff=ebdssbdestsearch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-womenconnect-new-york&quot;&gt;[FREE] WOMENCONNECT NEW YORK&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_THURSDAY, JUNE 07&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:30PM @ 350 5TH AVENUE_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LinkedIn NYC invites you to our very popular WomenConnect event series. Attendees will have the opportunity to hear from engineers across the company on both the latest technical projects we’re working on as well as what it means to be a woman in tech at LinkedIn. The goal of WomenConnect is for women who work in the tech industry to come together to network, build meaningful relationships and exchange professional best practices&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Please Note: RSVP close on Monday June 4th, 2018 at 11:59 PM EDT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://womenconnectnewyork.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;https://womenconnectnewyork.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;next-gen-summit&quot;&gt;Next Gen Summit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_June 8-10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;New York, NY_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next Gen was created with the idea that young people have the power to change the world. We’re not talking about 10 or 20 years from now, but today. We’re on a mission to find those innovators who dare to believe they can make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether you’ve already founded a company or are planning to turn an idea into reality, Next Gen Summit is your home. Over the course of the weekend, you will be challenged to dig deep and identify the best version of yourself, surrounded by hundreds of your fellow leaders from around the world. We hope to see you in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ngsummit.com/apply&quot;&gt;https://www.ngsummit.com/apply&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-family-astronomy-night&quot;&gt;[FREE] Family Astronomy Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Fri, June 8, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:30 PM – 10:00 PM EDT_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The universe is expanding—fast! The reason for this puzzling behavior is dark energy, a mysterious phenomenon that causes all stars and galaxies to run away from one another at an amazing pace. Hear from astrophysicist Viviana Acquaviva and discover what makes the universe accelerate and what will happen to it after billions of years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stargazing on the flight deck will follow the presentation (weather permitting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Family Astronomy Night will be primarily standing room only because of reduced seating capacity. Registration does not guarantee a seat.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:00pm: Doors open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:30pm: Presentation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:15pm–10:00pm: Stargazing and pop-up planetarium shows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/family-astronomy-night-tickets-44855360591?aff=es2&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/family-astronomy-night-tickets-44855360591?aff=es2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-art-a-hack&quot;&gt;[FREE] Art-A-Hack&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;June 9th - July 7th @ ThoughtWorks&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Art-A-Hack presents Special Edition 2018, a themed creative collaboration between groups of artists/engineers, designers/makers, scientists/dreamers etc. This special edition will take place at ThoughtWorks NY over &lt;strong&gt;four Saturdays from June 9th - July 7th&lt;/strong&gt;, with a final prototype presentation at CUNY City Tech’s theater in downtown Brooklyn on July 13th. Participation is FREE. We provide space, equipment, facilitation and advice, as well as a stellar showcase opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete info on the program and application here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://artahack.io/summer-2018/call/&quot;&gt;https://artahack.io/summer-2018/call/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coder-career-series-cracking-the-coding-interview&quot;&gt;Coder Career Series: Cracking The Coding Interview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wednesday, June 13, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:45 PM to 9:45 PM @ Byte Academy - 295 Madison Ave Fl 35_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Byte Academy (http://www.byteacademy.co/) is thrilled to host a Coder Career Series every other Wednesday with the Problem Solving Practice for Coders group. Byte instructor Kenso Trabing will lead most of the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The events will help attendees brush up on programming on-the-job or land that perfect job. Regulars range from people who recently learned how to code, to developers at the New York area’s top technology companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cracking the Coding Interview (5th or 6th edition) by Gayle Laakmann McDowell will be followed. Although the event will break individuals into groups to discuss the topics of choice, we’ll focus on a different chapter in each session. Coders of all different skills and languages are welcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will be a Meet and Greet and problem solving starts at 7:00 pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Byte-Academy-Finance-and-Technology-community/events/249362200/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/Byte-Academy-Finance-and-Technology-community/events/249362200/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-your-first-software-engineering-job-from-women-who-code-nyc&quot;&gt;[FREE] Your First Software Engineering Job From Women Who Code NYC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wednesday, June 13, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM to 9:00 PM @ Venmo - 159 West 25th Street, 9th floor_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are excited to be hosting a series of Lightning Talks on “Your First Software Engineering Job”. Several women will share their stories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;SCHEDULE:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;6:30-7:00 – Food and mingle
7:00-7:15 – Intros from WWC &amp;amp; Venmo
7:15-8:30 – Lightning Talks
8:30-9:00 – Network &amp;amp; Farewell’s&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/WomenWhoCodeNYC/events/250564618/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/WomenWhoCodeNYC/events/250564618/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-nyc-javascript-mini-bootcamp-fundamentals-i&quot;&gt;[FREE] [NYC] JavaScript Mini Bootcamp: Fundamentals I&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Sun, June 17, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10:00 AM – 4:30 PM EDT @ Hack Reactor - 369 Lexington Avenue, 11th Floor_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this workshop you will solidify your understanding of basic JavaScript, building up to the point that you are comfortable problem solving by writing simple functions with conditionals and for loops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a highly interactive course that uses exercises and projects to drive home these JavaScript Fundamentals. You will finish this course with in-depth knowledge of some of the most important aspects of the language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: Attending this workshop and the follow-up Fundamentals II workshop meets the prerequisite requirement for Hack Reactor’s Structured Study Program&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Functions, Conditionals and Loops&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-javascript-mini-bootcamp-fundamentals-i-tickets-45904267901&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-javascript-mini-bootcamp-fundamentals-i-tickets-45904267901&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-tech-jobs-tour-new-york-city--career-fair--speed-mentoring-with-megan-smith&quot;&gt;[FREE] Tech Jobs Tour New York City | Career Fair &amp;amp; Speed Mentoring with Megan Smith&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, June 19, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:00 PM – 9:00 PM @ Stage 48_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;America has over 500,000 open tech jobs – and over 60% of all new coders, engineers and data scientists are emerging from bootcamps and industry-current vocational schools. We are connecting the current and next generation of technical talent to companies who need their skills to grow and thrive in today’s economy. The #TechJobsTour will stop in over 50 U.S. cities in 2017 with one simple goal: help innovative companies hire America’s talent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more: &lt;a href=&quot;techjobstour.com&quot;&gt;techjobstour.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AGENDA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:00 PM Doors Open&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:00 - 9:00 PM Tech Career Fair&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5:30 PM Speed Mentoring I&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:00 PM Welcome by Tech Jobs Tour Team&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:20 PM Guest Speakers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:30 - 7:00 PM Speed Mentoring II (Lesbians Who Tech)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6:45 PM Keynote Speaker&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:00 PM Ask &amp;amp; Offer with Special Guests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7:15 PM Coding Bootcamp Showcase&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8:15 - 8:45 PM Speed Mentoring III&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9:00 PM Doors Close&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Details and registration: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/tech-jobs-tour-new-york-city-career-fair-speed-mentoring-with-megan-smith-3rd-cto-united-states-and-tickets-44573731230&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/tech-jobs-tour-new-york-city-career-fair-speed-mentoring-with-megan-smith-3rd-cto-united-states-and-tickets-44573731230&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-ethereum-solidity-blockchain-course&quot;&gt;[FREE] Ethereum Solidity Blockchain Course&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, June 19, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:00 PM – 9:00 PM EDT @ Rise New York_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chainhaus, NYC’s premiere blockchain training company, presents a developer workshop on Solidity!
Check out our other events http://chainhaus.eventbrite.com for early access to event tickets not announced yet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll spend 3 hours digging into Solidity and building some dapps. Developers will walk away with a strong grasp of Solidity and some of the development frameworks associated with it. This is perfect for beginners. You will learn TONS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the HUGE demand for this class, we ask that you only attend if you are ok with working on your laptop from your…errr…lap (no desks).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An email will be sent prior to course date on how to prepare your laptop for the prerequisite binaries. No installation support will be available during the class so please make sure your laptop has everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Class will start promptly at 6PM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit us at http://chainhaus.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/free-ethereum-solidity-blockchain-course-tickets-45819554521?aff=ehomecard&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/free-ethereum-solidity-blockchain-course-tickets-45819554521?aff=ehomecard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-raspberry-jam-at-mouse&quot;&gt;[FREE] Raspberry Jam at Mouse&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wed, June 20, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:00 PM – 8:00 PM @ 55 Broad Street, 16th Floor, New York, NY 10004_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raspberry Jams are community events for people to come together to learn about digital making with Raspberry Pi. Jam events come in all shapes and sizes: workshops for beginners, drop-in sessions to work on your own projects, show-and-tell, talks, and more. A Jam is a meeting of all kinds of people: some will be new to physical computing, and some will have plenty of experience that they are happy to share. Jams are welcoming events where you’ll meet and learn from like-minded people in a friendly environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Raspberry Jam is scheduled to coincide with the Picademy at Liberty Science Center, however everyone is welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/raspberry-jam-at-mouse-june-20-2018-tickets-44411673511?aff=ehomecard&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/raspberry-jam-at-mouse-june-20-2018-tickets-44411673511?aff=ehomecard&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101&quot;&gt;[FREE] Learn to Code Workshop: JavaScript 101&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wed, June 20, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7:00 PM – 9:30 PM EDT @ Hack Reactor_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Write JavaScript code while learning key JavaScript concepts in an interactive and friendly learning environment. Beginners welcome!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This class will kick you off on your journey of learning JavaScript and enable you to join a class of like-minded individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What JavaScript is used for and how it plays an important role in today’s ever-evolving technology ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How JavaScript works with web browsers to create interactivity on your favorite websites&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fundamental JavaScript concepts like syntax, variables, types, statements, expressions and functions&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who this workshop is for:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for learners with little to no JavaScript experience (complete beginners).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What to bring:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students will need to bring their own laptops! Windows, Mac or Linux will do it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101-tickets-45904542723&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/nyc-learn-to-code-workshop-javascript-101-tickets-45904542723&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-ai--machine-learning-in-the-real-world-a-panel-discussion&quot;&gt;[FREE] AI &amp;amp; Machine Learning in the Real World: A Panel Discussion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Wednesday, June 20, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM to 9:00 PM @ The Theater Center - 210 W 50th St, 4th Floor_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artificial Intelligence is one of the hottest tech topics of the summer, so we’ve invited a panel of experts to share everything we need to know about how AI and Machine Learning will affect our lives and businesses in the not-so-distant future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join Tech in Motion and our panel of speakers on Wednesday, June 20th to discuss the latest advancements and implications of Artificial Intelligence. Panel discussion topics will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A general understanding and intro to AI &amp;amp; Machine Learning Insights on what problems are worth solving with AI &amp;amp; Machine Learning Insights on ethics of AI in the workplace (and bias) Insights on the future of AI and Machine Learning And much more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;• 6:30 to 7:00pm – Event begins, networking, cocktails &amp;amp; hors d’oeuvres&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;• 7:15 to 8:00pm – Panel Discussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;• 8:00 to 8:15pm – Audience Q&amp;amp;A&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;• 8:15 to 8:30 - Event Wraps Up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;• After party to be announced during the panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seating Details (2 Options):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• Reserved Seating: Interested in reserving a seat(s) up front? -&amp;gt; Register through Eventbrite to reserve your guaranteed seat + 1 complimentary drink ticket! &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/ai-machine-learning-in-the-real-world-a-panel-discussion-tickets-46335914969&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/ai-machine-learning-in-the-real-world-a-panel-discussion-tickets-46335914969&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;• First-come, first-serve seating: RSVP via Meetup.com to ensure entry into the event. Theatre seating will be first-come first-serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-google-io-extended-bronx-2018-is-at-lehman-college&quot;&gt;[FREE] Google I/O Extended Bronx 2018 is at Lehman College&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Sat, June 23, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11:00 AM – 5:00 PM EDT @ Lehman College_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure not to miss Google I/O Extended 2018 where we will announce everything we are doing to promote software technologies and collaboration in the Bronx. #io18extended&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AGENDA:
We have a series of activities scheduled.
There will be Streaming of the Google I/O Event , Recap of what we saw and heard, Hands on Code Labs, Networking, Food, Fun, Swag on a Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see the Google I/O schedule we are using to build our agenda on go here https://events.google.com/io/schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Recruitment Form: https://goo.gl/aFG7Qc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To attend this event you must RSVP at: https://www.meetup.com/GDG-Bronx/events/248749750/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google Recruiters are coming to our event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-mongodb-world&quot;&gt;[FREE] MongoDB World&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;June 26th - 27th @ Hilton Midtown&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MongoDB is offering scholarships for underrepresented groups in tech to attend MongoDB World, an educational tech conference in NYC, &lt;strong&gt;June 26-27.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mongodb.com/mongodb-diversity-scholarship/?jmp=mtp&quot;&gt;https://www.mongodb.com/mongodb-diversity-scholarship/?jmp=mtp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-data-science-in-30-minutes-why-big-data-needs-thick-data-with-tricia-wang&quot;&gt;[FREE] Data Science in 30 Minutes: Why Big Data Needs Thick Data with Tricia Wang&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tue, June 26, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;5:30 PM – 6:30 PM EDT @ online (web series)_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join The Data Incubator and Tricia Wang, co-founder of Sudden Compass, for the next installment of our free online webinar series, Data Science in 30 Minutes: Why Big Data Needs Thick Data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract: Why do so many companies make bad decisions, even with access to unprecedented amounts of data? Tricia has the answer: companies are implementing “big data” without what she calls the secret, missing ingredient, “thick data”— precious, unquantifiable insights from actual people—to make the right business decisions and thrive in the unknown. She’ll share stories and lessons from how her company, Sudden Compass, advises and teaches organizations to unlock insights from big data and turn their big data projects from optimizing the bottom-line to driving growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-science-in-30-minutes-why-big-data-needs-thick-data-with-tricia-wang-tickets-45408159026?aff=es2&quot;&gt;https://www.eventbrite.com/e/data-science-in-30-minutes-why-big-data-needs-thick-data-with-tricia-wang-tickets-45408159026?aff=es2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;free-cybersecurity-nyc-inaugural-kick-off-night&quot;&gt;[FREE] Cybersecurity NYC Inaugural “Kick Off” Night&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;_Tuesday, June 26, 2018&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;6:30 PM to 8:30 PM @ Turn To Tech - 40 Rector Street, 10th Floor, suite 1000_&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for this inaugural event for Cybersecurity NYC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have a panel of cybersecurity professionals discussing the following topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1) Latest news in cybersecurity&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2) What are the different disciplines within the cybersecurity job market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3) What does it mean that NYC aspires to be the cybersecurity capital of the world?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4) With GDPR set to go into effect May 25, 2018, are U.S. companies taking the EU rules seriously? Will GDPR conflict with domestic U.S. regulations?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5) What certifications are most relevant in today’s job market?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6) What do YOU want to get out of future events of this meetup?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Food and drink will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RSVP here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meetup.com/Cybersecurity-NYC/events/ggzmrpyxjbjc/&quot;&gt;https://www.meetup.com/Cybersecurity-NYC/events/ggzmrpyxjbjc/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Join Us at our Interest Meeting in April!</title>
   <link href="lehmanwics.github.io/2018/03/16/wics-interest-meeting"/>
   <updated>2018-03-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>lehmanwics.github.io/2018/03/16/wics-interest-meeting</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Come talk about women in tech and computer science at the LC WiCS interest meeting on April 25th.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lehman College Women in Computer Science (WiCS) club at Lehman College is a new club on campus created to bring together women interested in technology and computer science at the Lehman campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interest meeting is intended to get to know you and learn more about what YOU would like to see WiCS bring to Lehman for you as a member. Come learn more about us and how you can get involved!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Location: &lt;/strong&gt; Carman Hall - 217&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pizza and refreshments will be served!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Register Here: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://meetlcwics.splashthat.com/&quot;&gt;https://meetlcwics.splashthat.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;lehmanwics.github.io/assets/images/flyer_event--wicsinterestmeeting.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>